Welcome, in the last lecture, we implemented this vaulting check for us to decide whether
欢迎，在上一次讲座中，我们实现了这个跳马检查，以决定我们是否可以开始跳马。
or not we can start vaulting.
是否可以开始跳伞。
And in this lecture, we'll look at how we can actually use this to start vaulting.
在这一讲中，我们将看看我们如何能够实际使用它来开始拱顶。
First, I'm going to take care of the editor stuff.
首先，我要处理一下编辑器的事情。
So I'm going to select this vaulting animation, double click to open it, go to asset details.
所以我将选择这个拱顶动画，双击打开它，进入资产细节。
I'm going to first enable this root motion.
我将首先启用这个根部动作。
If we don't take this, our motion morphing won't work later.
如果我们不这样做，我们的动作变形以后就不会工作。
And next thing, I'm going to create an element montage.
接下来，我将创建一个元素蒙太奇。
So right mouse button click, select create element montage.
所以鼠标右键点击，选择创建元素蒙太奇。
I'm going to name this am_vaulting and I'm going to move it to this montages folder,
我将把这个命名为am_vaulting，并把它移到这个蒙太奇文件夹、
select move here, then double click to open it and click pause in here.
选择移动这里，然后双击打开它，在这里点击暂停。
Then inside of this notify track in here, I'm going to right mouse button click and
然后在这里的通知轨道内，我将点击鼠标右键并
add notify state.
添加通知状态。
And I'm going to add in this motion morphing.
我将在这个运动变形中添加。
I'm going to increase the length of it.
我将增加它的长度。
So you can see we have a starting and an end point and the length of it will determine
所以你可以看到我们有一个起点和一个终点，它的长度将决定
how long it needs to warp the character to the target position.
它需要多长时间将角色扭曲到目标位置。
So I'm going to scroll to the frame when the character starts moving.
所以我将滚动到角色开始移动的那一帧。
So somewhere near here.
所以在这里附近的某个地方。
And I'm going to drag the starting point to here.
然后我将把起点拖到这里。
And as for the end point, so it will be when the character's hand reaches the surface.
至于终点，所以它将是角色的手到达表面的时候。
So somewhere near here, I think.
所以，我想是在这里附近。
Or here.
或者这里。
And with this end notifies state selected, I'm going to go to the drop down here.
选定这个终点通知状态后，我要到这里的下拉菜单去。
So click this drop down.
所以点击这个下拉菜单。
For this root motion modifier, I'm going to keep it at default.
对于这个根部运动修改器，我打算将它保持在默认状态。
And for this warp target name, I'm going to change it to vault start point.
对于这个翘曲的目标名称，我将把它改为拱顶的起始点。
And later in order for this to work, we'll need to have the exact same name in our C++.
为了使其发挥作用，我们需要在我们的C++中拥有完全相同的名称。
And go down for this warp translation, I'm going to take it and this EconautZ axis, I'm
对于这个经线平移，我打算把它和这个EconautZ轴，我打算取消它。
going to untick it.
取消勾选它。
So we do need to rely on this motion morphing to lift our character up.
所以我们确实需要依靠这种运动变形来提升我们的角色。
And if we don't do this, our vaulting just won't work later.
如果我们不这样做，我们的跳马就不会成功。
Alright, I'm also going to untick this warp rotation.
好吧，我也要取消这个翘曲旋转的勾选。
And for this translation, easing func, I'm going to change it to cubic.
对于这个平移，缓和函数，我将把它改为立方体。
Alright, that's pretty much what we need for this first motion morphing.
好了，这就是我们对第一个运动变形的基本需求。
And the second one.
还有第二个。
So we need to rely on the second one to move our character to the land position.
所以我们需要依靠第二个来移动我们的角色到陆地上的位置。
So I'm going to select this motion morphing, ctrl+c, then ctrl+v to copy it, then increase
所以我将选择这个运动变形，ctrl+c，然后ctrl+v复制它，然后增加它的长度。
its length.
它的长度。
So the second one should start at here.
所以第二个动作应该从这里开始。
Then it should end about here.
然后它应该在这里结束。
So right before our character lands.
所以就在我们的角色落地之前。
So somewhere around here.
所以在这里的某个地方。
Alright, for the second one, I'm going to change its warp token name to vault land point.
好的，对于第二个，我将把它的经线标记的名字改为拱顶着陆点。
And keep everything else the same as the first one.
并保持其他一切与第一个相同。
And that's pretty much it for this end of montage.
这就是这个蒙太奇结尾的基本内容。
I'm going to click save.
我将点击保存。
Then next thing we need to take care of the coding part.
然后，接下来我们需要处理编码部分。
So I'm going to close my project, select save, select it.
所以我将关闭我的项目，选择保存，选择它。
So inside of the code, there are a couple of things that we need to do.
所以在代码里面，有几件事情我们需要做。
First I'm going to create a function inside of this custom movement component.
首先，我将在这个自定义运动组件中创建一个函数。
So under this onClientMontage() edit, I'm going to create a new function.
所以在这个onClientMontage()编辑下，我将创建一个新的函数。
And I'm going to call it setMotionWarpTarget.
我将把它叫做setMotionWarpTarget。
And it's going to have two function inputs.
它将会有两个函数输入。
So the first one is going to be a const FName reference.
所以第一个将是一个const FName引用。
I'm going to call it inWarpTargetName.
我将把它称为inWarpTargetName。
And the second one is going to be a const FVector.
第二个将是一个常量FVector。
It's going to be a reference.
它将会是一个引用。
I'm going to call it int target position.
我将把它称为int target position。
All right, I'm going to create a function definition.
好的，我将创建一个函数定义。
And I'm going to place the function under this onClientMontage() edit.
我将把这个函数放在onClientMontage()的编辑下。
So place it in here.
所以把它放在这里。
And in this function, we'll need to access the motion morphing component from our character
在这个函数中，我们需要从我们的角色访问运动变形组件
class.
类。
For that, same as our nm instance, I'm going to create a variable to hold the reference
为此，与我们的NM实例一样，我将创建一个变量来保存我们角色的引用
of our character.
我们的字符的引用。
So go back to the header file, scroll down to this core variables.
所以回到头文件，向下滚动到这个核心变量。
I'm going to copy this empty U property and I'm going to forward declare the type of our
我将复制这个空的U属性，然后我将向前声明我们的
character.
字符的类型。
So go to its header file, copy this type.
所以去它的头文件，复制这个类型。
Go back to the movement component, paste it in here, add class in front of it.
回到运动组件，把它粘贴到这里，在它的前面加上类。
And I'm going to copy this type, go down and paste the type in here.
我将复制这个类型，下去把这个类型粘贴在这里。
I'm going to call this variable owning player character.
我将把这个变量称为拥有玩家角色。
And first, we need to assign some value values to this variable.
首先，我们需要给这个变量分配一些值。
So I'm going to go back to the CPP file of our character class, copy the first line,
所以我要回到我们角色类的CPP文件中，复制第一行、
go back to this custom moving component.cpp.
回到这个自定义移动组件.cpp。
I'm going to paste it in here.
我要把它粘贴到这里。
And don't forget to add the folder name in front of it.
别忘了在前面加上文件夹的名字。
And inside of the begin play, I'm going to get hold of it.
而在开始播放里面，我将掌握它。
So I'm going to cast from the type is going to be a climbing system character.
所以我要从类型中投出的将是一个攀登系统的角色。
So copy this, paste it in here.
所以复制这个，把它粘贴到这里。
And I'm going to cast from this character owner.
我将从这个角色的主人那里施放。
And I'm going to store that return result of this cast inside of our owning player character.
我将把这个投射的返回结果存储在我们自己的玩家角色中。
And just like that, I'm going to compile first.
就这样，我先进行编译。
I have a successful compile.
我有一个成功的编译。
And next thing I'm going to go back to my set motion more target function.
接下来，我将回到我的设置运动更多目标函数。
So inside of this function, I'm first going to check if this owning player character is
所以在这个函数中，我首先要检查这个拥有的玩家角色是否是
not valid.
不有效。
I'm going to return out of this function.
我将从这个函数中返回。
And once we get past this if check, I'm going to access the getter inside of our character
一旦我们通过了这个if检查，我将访问我们的角色内部的getter
class is called get motion warping component.
类的获取器，叫做获取运动扭曲组件。
And there's a function inside of this class.
在这个类里面有一个函数。
So for that we need to include is had a file, go back to the CPP file, file character class,
因此，我们需要在一个文件中加入这个功能，回到CPP文件中，在字符类文件中、
copy this line, paste it back to this custom moving component.cpp.
复制这一行，把它粘贴到这个自定义移动组件.cpp中。
Go down.
下去吧。
And the next function that we need to access is called at or update world target.
而我们需要访问的下一个函数被称为在或更新世界目标。
And you can see there are many versions that we can choose.
你可以看到有很多版本，我们可以选择。
I'm going to select this from location.
我将从位置中选择这个。
So there are two parameters we need to fill in the world target name and the target location.
所以有两个参数我们需要填写世界目标名称和目标位置。
And I'm going to fill in these two function inputs.
而我要填入这两个函数的输入。
So the first one is in world target name and the second one is in target position.
所以第一个是世界目标名称，第二个是目标位置。
All right, all there to do is to call this function inside of try start vaulting.
好了，所有要做的就是在尝试开始跳伞时调用这个函数。
So I'm going to copy this function, go back to try start vaulting.
所以我将复制这个函数，回到尝试开始跳伞的位置。
I'm going to delete these debug functions.
我将删除这些调试函数。
We don't need them anymore.
我们不再需要它们了。
I'm going to delete this one as well.
我也要删除这个。
So if this function returns true, I'm going to set the world target in here.
所以如果这个函数返回真，我将在这里设置世界目标。
So we need to fill in the world target name is going to be an F name and it should be
所以我们需要填入世界目标的名称，它将是一个F名称，应该是我们刚刚设置的名称。
the name that we just set.
它应该是我们刚刚设置的名称。
So it's called vault start point and I'm going to fill in this vault start position.
所以它被称为苍穹起点，我将填写这个苍穹起点位置。
So this is the starting position set and I'm also going to set the land position.
所以这是起始位置的设置，我也要设置土地位置。
So I'm going to change this name to vault endpoint and pass in this vault land position.
所以我要把这个名字改为金库终点，并传入这个金库的陆地位置。
All right, once we set the target for motion morphing, we also need to play the montage
好了，一旦我们设置了运动变形的目标，我们还需要播放蒙太奇
and for that we need another variable.
为此我们需要另一个变量。
So go back to my custom moving component, scroll down to this BPP variable.
所以回到我的自定义移动组件，向下滚动到这个BPP变量。
I'm going to create a new one.
我将创建一个新的。
So copy the old one, paste it in here.
所以复制旧的那个，把它粘贴到这里。
I'm going to change its name to vault montage and go back to the CPP file.
我要把它的名字改为vault montage，然后回到CPP文件。
Then here I'm going to call the function play client montage and pass in that vault montage
然后在这里我将调用函数play client montage并传入那个vault montage
and that's pretty much it.
这就差不多了。
Let's test this.
让我们测试一下这个。
I'm going to launch my editor back.
我将启动我的编辑器回来。
Go back to my editor and we're going to first go to my character class and assign the montage
回到我的编辑器，我们将首先进入我的角色类，把蒙太奇分配给
to the custom moving component.
到自定义的移动组件。
So for this vault montage, assign it this AM_Vaulting and click compile.
所以对于这个金库蒙太奇，把它分配给这个AM_Vaulting，然后点击编译。
Go back to my level.
回到我的水平。
I'm going to test it.
我准备测试一下。
So click play, go to this surface, press F and you can see it's not working.
所以点击播放，到这个表面，按F，你可以看到它没有工作。
Well actually it's working, but just not in the way we want.
实际上它在工作，但不是以我们想要的方式。
If I go to the side of this mesh, then press F again, you can see our character is in the
如果我走到这个网格的侧面，然后再按一次F，你可以看到我们的角色是在
moving, but we can't lift our character up to this surface.
移动，但我们不能把我们的角色抬到这个表面。
And the reason for that is we need to change our movement mode.
其原因是我们需要改变我们的运动模式。
So I'm going to go back to the montage and open this vaulting and I'm going to select
所以我将回到蒙太奇，打开这个拱顶，然后我将选择
this motion morphing.
这个运动变形。
Here we untick this ignore Z axis and in order for this to work, our character cannot
在这里，我们取消忽略Z轴的选项，为了使其发挥作用，我们的角色不能在行走模式中。
be inside of the walking mode.
我们的角色不能在行走模式中。
So we'll need to be inside of a movement mode that ignores gravity.
所以我们需要在一个无视重力的运动模式中。
And we have a custom mode just for that.
我们有一个自定义模式就是为了这个。
So I'm going to go back to my code and above this climb montage, I'm going to call the
所以我将回到我的代码中，在这个攀爬蒙太奇上面，我将调用
function start climbing.
函数开始爬升。
So this function here will set our movement mode to climbing and thanks to our hard work
所以这个函数将把我们的运动模式设置为攀爬。
in previous lectures, the movement physics has already been taken care of and the gravity
感谢我们在之前的讲座中的努力工作，运动物理学已经被处理好了，重力
will be ignored.
将被忽略。
And all it's left there to do is to set our movement mode back to walking when this montage
剩下要做的就是在这个蒙太奇完成后，将我们的运动模式设置为步行。
is finished the plane.
完成后，将我们的运动模式设为步行。
So I'm going to go back to this on climb montage ended.
所以我要回到这个爬升蒙太奇结束的地方。
So if the montage is equal to climb to top montage or the montage is equal to this vault
所以，如果这个蒙太奇等于爬到顶部的蒙太奇，或者这个蒙太奇等于这个拱顶的蒙太奇
montage, I'm going to set the movement mode back to walking.
蒙太奇，我就会把运动模式设置为步行。
All right.
好的。
I'm going to quickly save all then trigger live coding and go back to my project.
我将迅速保存所有然后触发实时编码，并回到我的项目。
I'm going to test it again.
我将再次测试它。
So click play, go to this match, press F and you can see this time is working.
所以点击播放，进入这个比赛，按F，你可以看到这次是成功的。
All right.
好的。
I'm going to increase the play rate of this montage.
我要增加这个蒙太奇的播放率。
So I'm going to increase it to two point one.
所以我要把它增加到两点一线。
I think right now it's too slow.
我认为现在它太慢了。
Click save and try again.
点击保存，再试一次。
Click play.
点击播放。
Go to this match.
转到这场比赛。
Press F. All right.
按F，好的。
You get the idea.
你明白了吧。
I think the two point one is too fast.
我认为2点1的速度太快了。
So I'm going to lower it down a bit, maybe to one point five and hit save.
所以我打算把它降低一点，也许是一点五，然后点击保存。
Try again.
再试一次。
Go to here, then click play.
转到这里，然后点击播放。
Press F. All right.
按F，好了。
Looking much better.
看起来好多了。
Go to this surface.
转到这个表面。
Yeah, something like that.
是的，类似这样的东西。
Maybe in here.
也许在这里。
So everything seems to be working, but actually there are still some errors.
所以一切似乎都在工作，但实际上仍然有一些错误。
So if I press F again, our character is in the vaulting, but it's still not behaving
所以如果我再按一次F，我们的角色就会进入拱顶，但它的行为仍然不是我们想要的。
the way we want.
我们想要的方式。
So if you recall back in the code, I've set the word target point to be the impact point
所以，如果你回想一下代码，我已经把字的目标点设置成了我们最后一行的影响点
of our last line trace.
我们最后一行的影响点。
But in here we are not reaching for that.
但是在这里，我们并没有达到这个目标。
And the reason for that is the mismatch of the word target name.
其原因是目标点的名称不匹配。
So I'm going to go back to this montage, double click to open it, and I'm going to select
所以我要回到这个蒙太奇，双击打开它，然后我将选择
the first motion morphing.
第一个动作变形。
You can see in here I have a typo.
你可以看到在这里我有一个错字。
So this name here is not the same as my code.
所以这里的名字和我的代码不一样。
I'm going to go back to my code and I'm going to scroll to this tristar vaulting.
我将回到我的代码，我将滚动到这个tristar vaulting。
And this is my name.
而这是我的名字。
So this is something that I'll need to double check later.
因此，这是我以后需要仔细检查的东西。
I'm going to copy this name in here and I'm going to paste it to here.
我要把这个名字复制到这里，并把它粘贴到这里。
And also for this second motion morphing, the name is different.
还有，对于这个第二个运动变形，名字是不同的。
So I'm going to go back to my code and I'm going to copy this name and I'm going to paste
所以我要回到我的代码中，复制这个名字并粘贴到
it in here.
它在这里。
And now I'm going to hit save and test this again.
现在我要点击保存并再次测试这个。
So click play and press F.
所以点击播放并按下F。
And this time it's working as expected.
这一次，它像预期的那样工作了。
Try again.
再试一次。
And this looks great.
这看起来很好。
I think the last line trace might be too far for this vaulting.
我想最后一条线的痕迹可能对这个跳马来说太远了。
I'm going to move the land point to be a bit closer to our character.
我打算把土地点移到离我们的角色近一点的地方。
So go back to my code.
所以回到我的代码中去。
Now instead of 4, I'm going to change it to 3.
现在我把它从4改成3。
Then quickly save all, trigger live coding.
然后快速保存，触发实时编码。
Alright live coding is accepted.
好了，实时编码被接受了。
I'm going to try again.
我再试一次。
Then press F. I think this distance here looks reasonable.
然后按F，我想这个距离看起来很合理。
Try again in here.
在这里再试一次。
Yeah, something like that.
是的，类似这样的事情。
We can even start vaulting in here.
我们甚至可以在这里开始跳楼。
And this looks natural enough, I think.
我认为这看起来足够自然。
And let's do a quick wrap up.
让我们做一个快速的总结。
So in order for this to work for animation, you first need to enable root motion and create
所以为了让这个动画工作，你首先需要启用根部运动并创建一个蒙太奇。
a montage from it.
一个蒙太奇。
After that, inside of that montage, you'll need to create an notified state for motion
之后，在这个蒙太奇中，你需要为运动创建一个通知状态
morphing and manually define the start and end point for the motion morphing notified
态，并手动定义运动变形通知状态的开始和结束点。
state.
状态。
After this one, you'll need to provide it with warp target name.
在这之后，你需要为它提供扭曲的目标名称。
Make sure you untick this ignore Z axis.
确保你取消勾选这个忽略Z轴。
Otherwise your motion morphing won't be able to lift the character up and make sure you
否则你的运动变形将无法将角色抬起来，并确保你
don't warp rotation.
不要扭曲旋转。
Since all we are interested in is the target location.
因为我们所关心的是目标位置。
Once you have the montage ready, we'll need to set the warp target in code.
一旦你准备好了蒙太奇，我们就需要在代码中设置翘曲的目标。
And later if the vaulting is not behaving in the way you want, double check the target
稍后如果拱顶的行为不符合你的要求，请仔细检查目标的
name.
名称。
And thanks to the debug functionalities that we have, that should be something pretty easy
由于我们拥有的调试功能，这应该是很容易
to spot.
发现。
And feel free to revert back to the video if you need help.
如果你需要帮助，可以随时回到视频中去。
Alright it's time for you to do the same.
好了，现在是时候让你做同样的事情了。
I'll see you in the next lecture.
我们在下一节课上见。
Bye for now.
暂时再见。